# CHAE-LIN KIM

**Q**2511 S Carrollton Ave, New Orleans, Louisiana, US

**(**(+1)504-864-9039, **S**ckim13@tulane.edu, **S**https://www.linkedin.com/in/chae-lin-kim/ **O**https://chaelin0722.github.io/introduction/

# PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently pursuing a Ph.D. in Computer Science at Tulane University, where I focus on AI-based assistive technology. My research interests include deep learning networks, particularly in the field of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and computer vision. I am passionate about developing technologies that enhance the quality of life.

# **EDUCATION**

Tulane University

PhD program in Computer Science

• Advisor: Professor Saad Hassan

**Sookmyung Women's University** 

Master of Engineering in IT Engineering

**Sookmyung Women's University** 

Bachelor of Engineering in IT Engineering(Magna Cum Laude)

Seoul, Korea

LA, United States

Aug. 2024 – present

Sep. 2021 – Aug. 2023 Seoul, Korea

Mar. 2016 – Aug. 2021

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Taean AI Industry Promotion Agency (TAIIPA)

Chungcheongnam-do, Republic of Korea

Research and Development of Artificial Intelligence Models in the Healthcare Sector

Nov. 2023 - Mar. 2024

• Conducted gait analysis to identify correlations between walking patterns and diseases, focusing on developing AI-driven solutions for health issues prevalent in Taean County's elderly community.

# The University of Akron

Ohio, US

Exchange Research Intern

July. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Applied deep learning algorithms to electrocardiogram classification.

### Sookmyung Women's University

Seoul, Republic of Korea

Development of deep Learning based vision inspection system for bamboo toothbrush

Sep. 2021 - Aug. 2023

- Proposed a deep learning-based fault detection model by improved Mask-RCNN with attention on FPN for manufacturing automation.
- Developed real-time parallel processing for a deep learning-based vision inspection system for the factory automation.

Evaluation of Speech Recognition on Foreign Language Education Services in Online Video Platform Environment

- Developed multi-modal model with vision and audio for Speech Recognition on Foreign Language Education Services.
- Designed lip syncing video from side face video using Rotation-and-Render and Wav2Lip model on Lip Reading task to solve the problem of difficulties on lip reading with side lips.

Few-shot learning for Facial Expression Recognition

- Propose channel selection module to select optimal channel features from support set and shows enhanced generalization performance
- Exploit spatial information from facial images and construct those additional data as support and query and shows generalization performance for each emotion category

#### JOURNAL PAPERS

# **International Journal**

1. Facial Expression Recognition with few-shot learning: A comprehensive survey, <u>Chae-Lin Kim(First)</u>, Byung-Gyu Kim\*, Journal of Real-Time Image Processing (Springer Nature) May 2023

# **International Conference**

- 1. Channel Selective Relation Network for Efficient Few-shot Facial Expression Recognition, Chae-Lin Kim(First), Ga-Eun Lee, Jiwoo Kang, Byung-Gyu Kim\* IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE) 2024
- 2. Recent Trend for Monocular Depth Estimation Based on Deep Learning, Ye-Ji Kim, <u>Chae-Lin Kim</u>, Han-Lim Lee and Byung-Gyu Kim\*, International Conference on Multimedia Information Technology and Applications (MITA)

### **Korean Conference**

- Integrated System for Facial Alignment and Lip Generation, Han-lim Lee, <u>Chae-Lin Kim</u>, Byung-Gyu Kim\*, and Kwang-Ho Kim, Spring Conference (KMMS) 2023
- 2. A Study of the Fault Detectifon Technique for the Bamboo Toothbrush Manufacturing Automation, <u>Chae Lin Kim(First)</u>, Young-Ju Choi, Byung-Gyu Kim\*, Eun-Ha Park, Kyung-Tae Lee, Autumn Conference (KMMS) 2022
- 3. Development of Real-time Dangerous Situation Detection Algorithm Based on Object Detection and Depth Information Fusion, **Chae Lin Kim(First)**, Jeong-Been Seo, Byung-Gyu Kim\*, Spring Conference (KMMS) 2021

# HONORS AND AWARDS

2nd place Award, DNA+ Drone Challenge, ETRI(Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute)	2022
Graduation with honors: magna cum laude, Sookmyung Women's University	2021
Best honors Award, Sookmyung Women's University	2021
High honors Award, Sookmyung Women's University	2017, 2020
1st Place Award, Java Hackathon in Jeju CCEI	2019
2nd place Award, Appjam in SOPT	2020
Undergraduate Research Scholarship, Sookmyung Women's University	2021

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### **Sookmyung Women's University** | *Teaching Assistant*

Seoul, Republic of Korea

### **Image Processing and its Applicatons**

March. 2022 - June. 2022

- Assist and teach MFC window programming with C language using Visual Studio
- Answered questions in person and online, marked assignments, and proctored exams for 30+ students

#### **Operating Systems Principles**

Sep. 2022 – Dec. 2022

- Assisted and helped examination paper creation about Operating Systems
- Answered questions in online, marked assignments and tests, and proctored exams for 280+ students

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

### **Graduate Student Council**

Seoul, Korea

Student President

March. 2022 - March. 2023

• Hosted meetings and conferences for professors and graduate students

# Sookmyung Unesco-Unitwin ICT education program

Phnom Penh, Cambodia

Student Assistant, Volunteer

Aug. 2020

Assisted Arduino and mobile application programming course and managed student hackathon project

### Sookmyung University Major Mentor Program (SUMM)

Seoul, Korea

IT Engineering Mentor

Sep. 2019 – Feb. 2021

• Delivered an introduction of IT Engineering lecture once a month and mentored high school students hoping to major in IT Engineering

# Java Programming Education in Jeju CCEI

Member of program

Jeju Island, Korea *July.* 2019 – Aug. 2019

• Designed a location based game application to solve social problems in Jeju island

# (SMWU-KSU Interdisciplinary) Hackathon with AWS Educate

Member of program

Seoul, Korea *Feb. 2020* 

• Proposed deep learning-based app service using text and vibration to alert dangerous situation for auditory disordered people

# **University student programming union club (SOPT)**

Seoul, Korea

Server Engineer

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019

• Designed an application service of vintage shopping mall as a server engineer and managed its database

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python (TensorFlow, Pytorch), HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Developer Tools: Git, Amazon Web Services, VS Code

Database: MySQL